Register of the Abortion Litigation Papers of Roy Lucas, 1967 - 1973
Abortion Litigation Papers of Roy Lucas, 1967 - 1973
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Lucas, Roy.
1000-187
14
28
Following graduation from New York University Law School in 1967, Roy Lucas published a landmark article, "Federal Constitutional Limitations on the Enforcement and Administration of State Abortion Statutes," in the North Carolina Law Review. Soon his interest in student rights and other civil liberties issues were overwhelmed as abortion litigation came to him in ever-growing volume. In 1969 and 1970 he helped found, with Morris Dees, the James Madison Constitutional Law Institute with offices in New York City and Montgomery, Alabama.
This collection documents state and federal abortion laws and court cases in the United States, spanning 1967-1973. It contains state and federal abortion litigation case files, documents, and correspondence; materials of the James Madison Institute; research files on aspects of abortion law, including studies of the Constitution and state laws on rights of the fetus; and publications regarding abortion and abortion laws including newspaper clippings about court cases.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Mr. Lucas agreed to place his closed files on abortion cases in the Wesleyan University Collection on Legal Change. The agreement was made in 1969 and a small volume of papers have been received from time to time until the Supreme Court's momentous abortion decision on January 22, 1973 in Roe v. Wade from Texas and Doe v. Bolton from Georgia. At this point a substantial file of papers from Roy Lucas was released to the Collection at Wesleyan.
Historical Note
Following graduation from New York University Law School in 1967, Roy Lucas published a landmark article, "Federal Constitutional Limitations on the Enforcement and Administration of State Abortion Statutes," in the North Carolina Law Review. Soon his interest in student rights and other civil liberties issues were overwhelmed as abortion litigation came to him in ever-growing volume. In 1969 and 1970 he helped found, with Morris Dees, the James Madison Constitutional Law Institute with offices in New York City and Montgomery, Alabama. In 1972 and 1973 this organization was changed somewhat to become the Population Law Center with offices in San Francisco and Washington, D. C.
Collection Overview
This collection documents state and federal abortion laws and court cases in the United States, spanning 1967 to 1973. It contains state and federal abortion litigation case files, documents, and correspondence; materials of the James Madison Institute; research files on aspects of abortion law, including studies of the Constitution and state laws on rights of the fetus; and publications regarding abortion and abortion laws including newspaper clippings about court cases.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series: Abortion Cases, Miscellaneous Correspondence, Lucas Papers, Miscellaneous Cases, Research, and Publications. The bulk of the material is contained within the first series on Abortion Cases, in which the materials are arranged by state, and then chronologically within each state.
Ms. Toby Singer, Wesleyan class of 1974, has undertaken the organization, the boxing and the description of these papers. The work was done in connection with a senior thesis project which took changes in abortion law as its subject. The description of Series and the Container List that follow are entirely the work of Ms. Singer.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Lucas, Roy.; Abortion--Law and legislation--United States.; Abortion--Law and legislation--United States--Cases.; Abortion--Law and legislation--United States--History.; Women's rights--United States--Cases.; Abortion--United States.; Legal documents.; Abortion--United States--History--20th century.; Trials (Abortion)--United States.; James Madison Institute.; Roe, Jane, 1947---Trials, litigation, etc.; Wade, Henry--Trials, litigation, etc.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Arizona.; Abortion--Law and legislation--California.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Colorado.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Connecticut.; Abortion--Law and legislation--District of Columbia.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Florida.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Georgia.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Iowa.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Kansas.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Kentucky.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Louisiana.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Maryland.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Massachusetts.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Michigan.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Minnesota.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Mississippi.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Missouri.; Abortion--Law and legislation--New Jersey.; Abortion--Law and legislation--New York (state).; Abortion--Law and legislation--North Carolina.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Ohio.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Oklahoma.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Pennsylvania.; Abortion--Law and legislation--South Dakota.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Texas.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Utah.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Vermont.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Virginia.; Abortion--Law and legislation--Wisconsin.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Abortion Cases
  Files of cases brought before state and federal courts including litigation papers and correspondence, arranged by state and chronologically within each state.
  - ARIZONA (Box 1)
    - Planned Parenthood v. Nelson (Box 1)
  - CALIFORNIA
    - California v. Belous (Box 1)
    - Major v. California -- Brief Amicus Curiae (Box 1)
    - Abortion Test Cases: Ali, Helth -All Decisions (Box 1)
    - Gwynne v. Hicks -- Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Calif.: Gwynne v. Hicks (Box 1)
    - Gwynne v. Hicks (Box 1)
      - Transcript of Proceedings (Box 1)
      - Petition for Writ of Prohibition (Box 1)
      - Petition for Hearing by Supreme Court (Box 1)
      - Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Overstreet v. Younger -- Drafts of complaint (Box 1)
      - Overstreet case (Box 1)
      - Litigation Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Extra Copies (Box 1)
      - Facts re: Plaintiff (Box 1)
      - Facts re: Abortion in Calif. (Box 1)
      - Drafts of Brief (Box 1)
      - Correspondence -- 3rd Party (Box 1)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 1)
    - California v. Barksdale (Box 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 1)
      - Request to file Brief Amicus Curiae (2 copies) (Box 1)
      - Brief of Amicus Curiae (Lucas) (Box 1)
      - Brief of Amici Curiae (ZPG) (Box 1)
      - Answer to Brief Amicus Curiae (Robb) (Box 1)
      - Answer to Brief Amicus Curiae (Musick) (Box 1)
      - Decisions (Box 1)
    - California v. Pettigrew -- Opinions (Box 2)
  - COLORADO (Box 2)
    - Doe v. Dunbar (Box 2)
      - Original Litigation Papers (Box 2)
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - Memorandum of Law (Box 2)
      - Appendix II to Memorandum of Law (Box 2)
      - Litigation Papers (copies) (Box 2)
      - Facts (Box 2)
      - (Box 2)
  - CONNECTICUT (Box 2)
    - Abele v. Markle -- Litigation Papers (Box 2)
  - DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA (Box 2)
    - U.S. v. Verges (Box 2)
    - WONAAC v. D.C. Council (Box 2)
      - Working Copy of Record (Box 2)
      - Record -- Vol. I (Box 3)
      - Record -- Vol. II (Box 3)
      - No. III (Box 3)
      - No. IV (Box 4)
    - Coleman, Summit v. Washington (Box 4)
      - Complaint (Extras) (Box 4)
      - Record (Box 4)
    - Pre-Birth v. Nevius (Box 4)
      - Complaint (Extras) (Box 4)
      - Record (Box 4)
    - Preterm v. Washington (Box 4)
      - Record Vol. I (Box 4)
      - Record Vol. II (Box 4)
    - U.S. v. Vuitch (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (Box 4)
      - Research -- Vagueness (Box 4)
      - Research -- Jurisdiction (Box 4)
      - Research -- Privacy (Box 4)
      - Litigation Papers (copies) (Box 4)
      - Litigation Papers (Briefs) (Box 5)
      - Clippings (Box 5)
    - D.C. Abortion Cases: Affidavit (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. Vuitch -- Memorandum Opinion (Box 5)
    - Patient Residence Study (Box 5)
    - U.S. v. Vuitch (Box 5)
      - Motion to Affirm (2 copies) (Box 5)
      - Brief (Box 5)
  - FLORIDA
    - Florida v. Auslander -Record (Box 5)
    - Militana v. Univ. of Miami -- Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Militana case (Box 5)
      - Petition for Writ of Certiorari (Box 5)
      - Opinions (Box 5)
    - Poe v. Gerstein -- Jurisdictional Statement (Box 5)
  - GEORGIA
    - Doe v. Bolton -- Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Criminal Code of Georgia (Box 5)
    - Doe v. Bolton (Box 5)
      - Motion to Intervene (2 copies) (Box 5)
      - Amicus Draft (Box 5)
      - Brief Amicus Curiae (2 copies) (Box 5)
      - Transcript of Oral Argument (Box 6)
      - Opinions (Box 6)
      - Brief Amicus Curiae against Rehearing (Box 6)
      - Supplemental Appendix to Brief Amicus Curiae (3 copies)> (Box 6)
  - IOWA (Box 6)
    - Smith v. Iowa Liquor Control Commission -- Record (Box 6)
    - Tinker v. DesMoines -- Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Tinker case -- Briefs (Box 6)
    - Tinker v. DesMoines -- Opinions (Box 7)
  - KANSAS (Box 7)
    - State v. Jamieson -- Letter from Roy Lucas (files returned) (Box 7)
    - Stapleton v. Mitchell -- Opinion (Box 7)
    - Douglass Hospital: General Correspondence (Poe v, Menghini) (Box 7)
    - Douglass Hospital: Litigation (Box 7)
    - Douglass Hospital: Weller (Box 7)
    - Linda Gutknecht case -- Facts (Box 7)
    - Douglass Hospital case -- Hospitals in Kansas (Box 7)
    - Douglass Hospital case -- Attorney General Opinion (Box 7)
    - A Guide to Problem Pregnancy Counseling (Box 7)
    - Poe v. Menghini (Box 7)
      - Set of Supplemental Brief and Exhibits (Box 7)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 7)
      - Notes (Box 7)
      - Opinions (Box 7)
    - Mounted News Clippings (Box 7)
    - Poe v. Menghini -- Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - KENTUCKY (Box 7)
    - Crossen v. Breckenridge -- Memorandum of Law (Box 7)
  - LOUISIANA (Box 7)
    - Knight v. Louisiana State Board of Medical Examiners (Box 7)
    - Louisiana: Rosen v. Board (Box 7)
      - Facts, Trial, Data (Box 7)
      - Correspondence (Box 7)
      - State Law Matters (Box 7)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 7)
      - Rosen v. Louisiana State Board -- Jurisdictional Statement (Box 8)
      - Rosen v. Board -- Litigation Papers (Box 8)
      - Rosen v. Louisiana State Board -- Decisions (Box 8)
    - Louisiana v. Scott (Box 8)
  - MARYLAND (Box 8)
    - Lashley v. Maryland (Box 8)
    - Maryland: Vuitch v. Maryland (Box 8)
      - Preliminary Drafts (Box 8)
      - Copies of Briefs and Litigation Papers (Box 8)
      - Petition for Writ of Certiorari (Box 8)
      - Brief of Amici Curiae (3 copies) (Box 8)
    - State v. Vuitch (Towsen case) -- Exhibits to Brief (Box 8)
    - Vuitch v. Maryland (Box 8)
      - Appendix A for Amici Curiae (Box 8)
      - Appendix B (Box 8)
    - Maryland: Vuitch v. Maryland (Box 8)
      - Facts re: Hospitals (Box 8)
      - State Law (Box 8)
      - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Maryland v. Vuitch -- Litigation Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Vuitch v. State (II) -- Litigation Papers and Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Vuitch v. Maryland -- Litigation Papers (Box 9)
    - Maryland v. Vuitch -- Litigation Papers (2) (Box 9)
    - Maryland Abortion: Clippings (Box 9)
    - Maryland v. Vuitch -- Opinions (Box 9)
    - Vuitch v. Hardy (Box 9)
      - Correspondence (Box 9)
      - Litigation Papers and Correspondence (3) (Box 9)
      - Appeal and/or Application for Bail (Box 9)
      - Research Material -- Merits (Box 10)
      - CA4 -Research Material -- Merits (Box 10)
      - Record (2) (Box 10)
      - CA4 (Box 10)
    - Accreditation Manual for Hospitals (Box 10)
    - Exhibit C -- Maryland Hospital Standards (2 copies) (Box 10)
    - Hardy v. Vuitch -- Brief of Appellee (5 copies) (Box 10)
    - Hardy v. Vuitch (Box 11)
      - Brief of Appellee (5 copies) (Box 11)
      - Joint Appendix (2 copies) (Box 11)
      - Brief of Respondent 1971 (2 copies) (Box 11)
      - Brief of Respondent 1972 (Box 11)
    - Vuitch v. Hardy -- Opinions (Box 11)
    - State v. Ingel (Box 11)
      - Post-conviction Research (Box 11)
      - Post-conviction Record (Box 11)
      - Record -- RL Copy (Box 11)
      - Research (Box 11)
      - Brief and Exhibits (Box 11)
  - MASSACHUSETTS (Box 12)
    - Commonwealth v. Hare (Box 12)
  - MICHIGAN (Box 12)
    - Michigan Abortion Case -- State v. Ketchum (Box 12)
    - Beebe v. Calahan (Box 12)
    - Mitchell v. City of Royal Oak (Box 12)
    - Beechnau v. Austin (Box 12)
    - Poe v. Scodeller (Box 12)
      - Litigation Correspondence (Box 12)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 12)
        - Marked Set (Box 12)
        - File Set (Box 12)
        - Extra Copies (Box 12)
      - Plaintiffs' Exhibit C: Means Article (Box 12)
  - MINNESOTA (Box 12)
    - Doe v. Randall (Box 12)
      - State Court Prosecution (Box 12)
      - State Law Aspects (Box 12)
      - Correspondence (Box 12)
      - Minnesota Writ of Prohibition (Box 12)
      - Minnesota Case (Box 12)
      - Jurisdictional Statement: Drafts (Box 12)
    - Doe v. Randall (Box 13)
      - Facts (Box 13)
      - Appearances (2 copies) (Box 13)
      - Original Litigation Papers (Box 13)
    - Hodgson: State (Box 13)
      - Amicus Correspondence (Box 13)
      - Sharood Correspondence (Box 13)
      - 3rd Party Correspondence (Box 13)
      - Perry Correspondence (Box 13)
      - Litigation Correspondence (Box 13)
      - Bills, Expenses and Defense Fund (Box 13)
    - Hodgson v. Minnesota -- Fetal Status in Minnesota (Box 13)
    - Hodgson (Box 13)
      - Minnesota Supreme Court Cases (Box 13)
      - Legislative History (Box 13)
    - Hodgson v. Minnesota (Box 13)
      - Rubella Data (Box 13)
      - Rubella Practice (Box 13)
    - Rubella -- Effects -- Studies pre-1964 Epidemic (Box 13)
    - Rubella -- Effects -Studies re: 1964 Epidemic (Box 13)
    - Rubella -- Vaccination -- Effect (Box 13)
    - Rubella -- Vaccination, Vaccines -- Extent (Box 13)
    - JH -- Cases (Box 13)
    - Barno (Box 13)
    - Bernstein (Box 13)
    - Bob McCoy (Box 14)
    - McKelvey (Box 14)
    - Joe Pratt (Box 14)
    - Witnesses (Box 14)
    - Mecklenburg and M.C.C.L. (Box 14)
    - Exhibits (Box 14)
    - Exhibits 10-15 Re: Cooper (Box 14)
    - Order of Trial (Box 14)
    - Dr. Hodgson -- Questions (Box 14)
    - Hodgson: State: Drafts of Minnesota Supreme Court Brief (Box 14)
    - Hodgson v. Minnesota (Box 14)
      - Draft of Brief (Box 14)
      - Final Draft of Brief (Box 14)
      - Jurisdictional Statement (2 copies) (Box 14)
      - Jurisdictional Statement (Box 14)
      - Appellant's Brief (3 copies) (Box 14)
    - Minnesota v. Hodgson -- Transcript of Criminal Proceedings (Box 14)
    - Hodgson; State: District Court Opinion and Verdict and Judgment (Box 14)
    - Hodgson v. Minnesota -- Articles (Box 14)
    - Hodgson: State: Clippings (Box 14)
    - Minnesota v. Hultgren (Box 14)
  - MISSISSIPPI (Box 14)
    - McCaskill v. Mississippi (Box 14)
  - MISSOURI (Box 14)
    - State v. Burnside (Box 14)
    - Rodgers v. Danforth (Box 15)
      - Correspondence (Box 15)
      - Facts (Box 15)
      - Legislative Research -- State (Box 15)
      - Original Litigation Papers (Box 15)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 15)
      - Litigation Papers -- Copies (Box 15)
  - NEW JERSEY (Box 15)
    - YWCA v. Kugler -- New Jersey Abortion Case (Box 15)
    - New Jersey Abortion Case -- Brief Mailings (Box 15)
    - New Jersey Abortion Cases -- Memoranda and Cases (Box 15)
    - New Jersey State Law (Box 15)
      - Abortion Cases (Box 15)
      - Foetus Status (Box 15)
    - YWCA v. Kugler (Box 15)
      - Marked Documents (Box 15)
      - Litigation Papers (2) (Box 15)
      - Brief of Plaintiffs (Box 16)
      - Appendix A (2 copies) (Box 16)
      - Appendix B (Box 16)
      - Appendix C (Box 16)
      - Opinion (Box 16)
  - NEW YORK (Box 16)
    - Doe v. Lefkowitz (Box 16)
      - Memoranda of Law (Box 16)
      - Brief (Box 16)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 16)
    - Hall v. Lefkowitz (Box 16)
    - Hall -- Questionnaires Returned (Box 16)
    - Hall v. Lefkowitz (Box 16)
      - Background Facts (Box 16)
      - New York Law and Interpretation (Box 17)
      - Equal Protection (Box 17)
      - Cruel and Unusual Punishment (Box 17)
      - Free Expression (Box 17)
      - Bias and Due Process (Box 17)
    - Dr. Corner -- Deposition (Box 17)
    - Cushner Deposition (Box 17)
    - PP -- NYC Deposition (Box 17)
    - Ober Deposition (Box 17)
    - Pf Hall Deposition (Box 17)
    - Tietze Deposition (Box 17)
    - Pf Hellman Deposition (Box 17)
    - Pf Guttmacher Deposition (Box 17)
    - Papers Re, Pf Romney (Box 17)
    - Hall v. Lefkowitz (Box 17)
      - Correspondence (Box 17)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 17)
      - Motions to Intervene (Box 17)
      - Orders, Opinions, Judgments (Box 17)
    - D'Javid v. Lefkowitz (Box 17)
    - Hall v. Hogan (Box 18)
      - Correspondence (Box 18)
      - Brief of Plaintiffs (3 copies) (Box 18)
      - Appendix D (4 copies) (Box 18)
      - Brief Amicus Curiae (Box 18)
    - Hall v. Ingraham (Box 18)
    - Hall and Poe v. Columbia Presbyterian (Box 18)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous Notes on Facts (Box 18)
    - Hall v. Columbia Presbyterian -N.Y. Statutes Generally Minors (Box 18)
    - Columbia Presbyterian Guidelines on Abortion (Box 18)
    - Columbia Presbyterian, State and Federal Aid (Box 18)
    - Hall and Poe, Clippings (Box 18)
    - Heumann v. Board of Education -- Complaint and Drafts (Box 18)
    - Heumann case: (Box 18)
      - Prior Administrative Proceeding (Box 18)
      - Motions and Memoranda (Box 18)
      - Litigation Papers and Correspondence (Box 18)
      - Correspondence with Third Parties (Box 18)
      - Clippings, Releases, etc. (Box 18)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 18)
    - Heumann v. Board of Education (Box 18)
      - Letters, Affidavits, etc. (Box 18)
      - Generalized Legal Ramblings (Box 18)
    - Heumann Case, Litigation -Marked Copies (Box 19)
    - Heumann v. Board of Education (Box 19)
      - Correspondence re: Other Cases (Box 19)
    - Byrn v. N.Y.C. Hospitals (Box 19)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 19)
      - Copies of Litigation Papers (Box 19)
    - Mitchell v. Lefkowitz (Box 19)
      - Litigation Papers and Correspondence (Box 19)
      - Copies of Litigation Papers (Box 19)
      - Memorandum of Law for 3-Judge Court (Box 19)
    - Delta's Papers (Box 19)
    - SPS and Mitchell -- Draft Brief (Box 19)
    - SPS v. Lefkowitz (Box 19)
      - Affidavit (Box 19)
    - Overton v. Rieger (Box 20)
      - Brief for Appellant (2 copies) (Box 20)
      - Reply Brief for Appellants (Box 20)
  - NORTH CAROLINA
    - Keenan v. Board of Bar Examiners -- N.C. Bar Residence Case (Box 20)
    - Corkey v. Edwards (Box 20)
      - General Correspondence (Box 20)
      - Drafts of J.S. (Box 20)
      - Jurisdictional Statement (3 copies) (Box 20)
      - Motion to Set Q's IV-VI for Argument (Box 20)
  - OHIO (Box 21)
    - Steinberg v. Rhodes -- Jurisdictional Statement (Box 21)
    - Ohio: Steinberg: (Box 21)
      - Litigation Correspondence (Box 21)
      - Correspondence with Third Parties (Box 21)
      - Drafts of Jurisdictional Statement (Box 21)
      - Useful Data (Box 21)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 21)
      - State Law on Abortion (Box 21)
      - Tort and Property Law (Box 21)
      - Clippings (Box 21)
  - OKLAHOMA (Box 21)
    - Henrie v. Blankenship -- Oklahoma State Law (Box 21)
    - Henrie: Oklahoma (Box 21)
      - Federal Habeas Corpus and Jurisdiction (Box 21)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 21)
    - Oklahoma Case -- Clippings (Box 21)
    - Henrie, Bryan M.D. -- Abortion Prosecution (Box 21)
    - Henrie v. Blankenship (Box 21)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 21)
    - Dr. Henrie's Manuscripts (Box 21)
  - PENNSYLVANIA (Box 21)
    - McGarvey v. Magee -- Women's Hospital (Box 21)
  - SOUTH DAKOTA (Box 22)
    - South Dakota: Munson v. South Dakota -- U.S. Supreme Court Record (Box 22)
    - South Dakota Abortion Case: Opinion -- South Dakota Supreme Court (Box 22)
    - Munson v. South Dakota -- Jurisdictional Statement (4 copies) (Box 22)
    - South Dakota v. Munson -- Respondents' Brief (Box 22)
    - South Dakota: State v. Munson (Box 22)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 22)
      - Correspondence (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
      - State Law Aspects (Box 22)
  - TEXAS (Box 22)
    - Veevers v. Texas (Box 22)
    - Tate v. Short (Texas) (Box 22)
    - Tex.: Roe v. Wade: Correspondence (Box 22)
    - Roe v. Wade -- Litigation Papers (2) (Box 22)
    - Tex.: Roe v. Wade (Box 23)
      - Argument on Jurisdiction (Box 23)
      - Jurisdictional Statement (Drafts) (Box 23)
      - Jurisdictional Statement (Copies) (Box 23)
    - Jurisdictional Statement -- Appendix (Box 23)
    - Tex.: Roe v. Wade: Clippings (Box 23)
    - Roe v. Wade (Box 23)
      - State Law Matters (Box 23)
      - Draft of Brief (Box 23)
      - Brief for Appellants (7 copies) (Box 23)
      - Brief for Amicus Curiae (Box 24)
      - Supplemental Brief for Appellants (Box 24)
      - Brief Amicus Curiae -- Rehearing (Box 24)
      - Oral Argument (Box 24)
    - Tex.: Roe v. Wade: Opinion (copies) (Box 24)
    - New York Times, January 23, 1973 (Box 24)
  - UTAH (Box 24)
    - Utah Abortion Test Case: Doe v. Rampton (Box 24)
  - VERMONT (Box 24)
    - Vermont v. Bartlett (Box 24)
    - R. V. Leahy (Box 24)
      - Correspondence (Box 24)
      - Litigation Papers (Box 24)
  - VIRGINIA
    - Baines v. Damville (Box 24)
    - Virginia Abortion Case: State v. Smitherman (Box 24)
  - WISCONSIN (Box 24)
    - Harling v. Department of Health and Social Services (Box 24)
    - Wisconsin case: Babbitz v. McCann (Box 24)
    - Wisconsin: Kennan case (Box 24)
      - State Papers (Box 24)
      - Federal Litigation Papers (Box 24)
      - Correspondence re: Litigation (Box 24)
      - Clippings (Box 24)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence
  Correspondence which cannot be filed within specific cases, arranged chronologically
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969-1973, undated (Box 25)
- Lucas Papers
  Papers concerning Roy Lucas including tapes of conversations, materials of the James Madison Institute and other miscellaneous material.
  - Lucas, Roy (1942- ?) (Box 25)
  - Tapes of interview with Clement E. Vose, 1973 February 4 (Box 25)
  - Transcript of tapes of interview (Box 25)
  - Transcript of "Firing Line" (4 copies), 1972 July 25 (Box 25)
  - James Madison Constitutional Law Institute (Box 25)
- Miscellaneous Cases
  Files from cases which were sent separately from the Abortion Cases and at a later time, arranged alphabetically.
  - Decisions: DEF's EXl -- RL Set (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Cases (Box 25)
  - Abramowitz v. Lefkowitz (Box 25)
  - Jobe v. Oklahoma -- Brief of Plaintiff (Box 25)
  - Lyons v. Lefkowitz (Box 25)
  - Morin v. Garra (Box 26)
    - Certiorari Petition, Other Papers, Record (Box 26)
    - Petition for Writ of Certiorari (Box 26)
    - Brief for Defendants/Respondents (Box 26)
    - Brief for Plaintiffs/Appellants (Box 26)
    - Appendix to Appellants' Brief (Box 26)
    - Petition for Certification (Box 26)
    - Supplemental Petition for Certification (Box 26)
  - Ornick v. Idaho Board of Education -Nonresident (Box 26)
  - Litigation Correspondence (Box 26)
  - Poe v. Nixon (Box 26)
- Research
  Files of research about aspects of abortion laws, including studies of the Constitution and state laws regarding the rights of the fetus.
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 27)
  - Note cards (Box 27)